<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-15T00:32:09+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vienna Blog</title><subtitle>A (nearly) no-CSS, fast, minimalist Jekyll theme.
#favicon: &quot;logo.png&quot; # name+extension of favicon (which must be put on the root folder)
</subtitle><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><entry><title type="html">Christmas Markets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/14/christmasmarkets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas Markets" /><published>2021-11-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/14/christmasmarkets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/14/christmasmarkets.html">&lt;p&gt;There are Christmas markets and I took photos!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">There are Christmas markets and I took photos!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/IMG_20211112_180154815.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/IMG_20211112_180154815.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interiors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/17/interiors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interiors" /><published>2021-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/17/interiors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/17/interiors.html">&lt;p&gt;I really like seeing the inside of residential buildings in different countries for the same reason I like going grocery shopping when I travel: I like imaging I actually live somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently I still feel this way when I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; live in a foreign country because I was very happy to help my housemate pick up various secondhand pieces of furniture as an excuse to be nosy and see cool courtyard entrances like this: 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/interiors/courtyard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;court&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’m not creepy about it and was actually invited to my friends’ houses. I don’t know why I like her kitchen so much but I like that you really couldn’t find something like this in the US. I think the ceilings are 12 feet? 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/interiors/kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">I really like seeing the inside of residential buildings in different countries for the same reason I like going grocery shopping when I travel: I like imaging I actually live somewhere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Opera</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/16/opera.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opera" /><published>2021-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/16/opera</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/16/opera.html">&lt;p&gt;I attended my first opera, kind of by mistake! The woman who was my host mom when I was here in high school invited me to see something that I understood involved opera and was called Peter Grimes. I thought that was the name of a tenor or something who might perform some arias but no, it’s a whole opera. (“Oh, a modern one!” is the response from the two people I know who would not have made my same mistake. Modern means the 40s.)
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/opra/ticket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ticket&quot; /&gt;
It was a cool experience though, especially since Cynthia is the kind of person who knows everyone. We went back stage during the intermission and one of the performers gave me chocolate pudding.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/opra/stage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;stage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">I attended my first opera, kind of by mistake! The woman who was my host mom when I was here in high school invited me to see something that I understood involved opera and was called Peter Grimes. I thought that was the name of a tenor or something who might perform some arias but no, it’s a whole opera. (“Oh, a modern one!” is the response from the two people I know who would not have made my same mistake. Modern means the 40s.) It was a cool experience though, especially since Cynthia is the kind of person who knows everyone. We went back stage during the intermission and one of the performers gave me chocolate pudding.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bosna</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/14/bosna.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bosna" /><published>2021-10-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/14/bosna</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/14/bosna.html">&lt;p&gt;I went to see a show for a cool band I found by searching through Viennese bands on bandcamp. It was on a Thursday night with 8am class the next morning but totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alexfranzzehetbauer.com/about&quot;&gt;The opener&lt;/a&gt; was a guy dressed in cow print flares stomping around with a microphone in one hand and a speaker in the other. The venue is also a hotel? So he would slam in and out of different rooms while coughing hoarsely. When he eventually made it to the stage he created feedback for about 10 minutes and then stood and sung a classically beautiful song.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/bosna/opener.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;open&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The act I was really excited about was great, honestly I just suggest you listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 42px;&quot; src=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1647407294/size=small/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/track=3549092373/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://numavi.bandcamp.com/album/you-know-too-much&quot;&gt;You Know Too Much by BOSNA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/bosna/bosna.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bosna&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contemporaneous notes (texted enthusiastically to a friend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But anyway, I’m at this noise show that is super cool and wow is it nice to live in a city cheap enough that someone can just be occupied doing weird shit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And the venue is super cool, old tiny stage but they built seating risers where the stage used to be so it’s like looking into the audience while watching the show&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">I went to see a show for a cool band I found by searching through Viennese bands on bandcamp. It was on a Thursday night with 8am class the next morning but totally worth it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">School</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="School" /><published>2021-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/school</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/school.html">&lt;p&gt;One of my first days in Vienna I went to check out campus since I was living nearby at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t gone into the library yet because covid limitations plus a reservation system I can’t figure out means I keep getting turned away. The outside has this funky 70s owl that I’m quite fond of though. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/owl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;owl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some architectural whiplash, the main campus is near Karlsplatz:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/karl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;karl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS building isn’t as impactful but I do like the metal letters floating over the building.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/csbuilding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first school event was an orientation that included free beer :’) and turned into more late night beers in the courtyard and then even later beers in the park in front of the church. The amount of casual outside drinking blows my mind every time it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, this is the first day that I started to realize my worries about making new friends would be overblown. I think it’s a combination of the school mindset–people are in meet-new-people mode–and the reopening after covid mindset that make it easier here than it was when I interned different places for instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;intro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">One of my first days in Vienna I went to check out campus since I was living nearby at the time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leaving</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/23/leaving.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leaving" /><published>2021-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/23/leaving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/23/leaving.html">&lt;p&gt;Got down to three bags + backpack before leaving the US in September.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/stuff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;stuff&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why Vienna?” is a question I get from a lot of people (especially the locals) so I feel like I have my set of answers at this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was ready for a change in scenery but wasn’t excited enough about any particular place in the US to try to move there. I also credit my friend Marina as a major inspiration/role model because she actually acted on the feeling that she needed a change of pace even if life at home was good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I speak some German (quickly and quietly so people don’t catch my mistakes or anything at all that I’m saying) but the program is in English so I don’t need to speak &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much German.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a great deal! School is much cheaper, even for a master’s degree unlike some of the cash cow masters degrees at home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have some friends from home who live here and can help me when I need it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel like I didn’t take enough advantage of the summer I spent here in high school so this is round 2!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The program is surprisingly exactly what I want to do: a master’s degree in CS that focuses on math, formal methods, and logic instead of generic software development or a specialty that doesn’t interest me like machine learning. When I found it I felt a little like the stars were aligning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a retroactive blog post but all the reasoning above has held up and the transition has been surprisingly smooth!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">Got down to three bags + backpack before leaving the US in September.</summary></entry></feed>