<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-08T16:08:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vienna Blog</title><subtitle>A (nearly) no-CSS, fast, minimalist Jekyll theme.
</subtitle><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><entry><title type="html">Cafe Central</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/02/01/central.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cafe Central" /><published>2022-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/01/central</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/02/01/central.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s maybe the least hidden gem kind of place to go but I really like Cafe Central. I won’t stand in line to get in but I will get out of the house kind of early on a Tuesday and then read a logic book in a &lt;em&gt;salon&lt;/em&gt; (put some kind of accent on that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The children (Hannah and my friend Felicia who is also doing this master’s) tell me this is called “romanticizing your life” but I don’t really have to put any force of will behind it when the ceilings are this nice:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ceiling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">It’s maybe the least hidden gem kind of place to go but I really like Cafe Central. I won’t stand in line to get in but I will get out of the house kind of early on a Tuesday and then read a logic book in a salon (put some kind of accent on that).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Birthday/Exams</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/22/birthday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Birthday/Exams" /><published>2022-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/22/birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/22/birthday.html">&lt;p&gt;Had a great birthday! I got to go to my favorite market and then spend the day cooking for a relatively large group of groups of friends (15 people maybe?). Not a bad start to my late 20s (thanks for pointing out that milestone Han).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone got along and everyone got negative covid tests before they came over. I don’t have any pictures of before the party and I don’t have the full aftermath either but here’s halfway through cleanup:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/bday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spritzers are a genius drink because you stay really hydrated. Since Europeans from a wine producing country invented it adding seltzer to your wine becomes acceptable somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No smelly pile of oyster shells to deal with like my last big birthday party (god I miss fish).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flour is different here, a cake recipe I’ve made plenty of times was a greasy mess. Everyone still told me it was good and now I have trust issues. Thankfully two other cakes were contributed, one of them an official Sachertorte in a wrapped wooden box that I refuse to check the cost on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately my birthday was roughly in the middle of exams, which are roughly in the middle of the end of classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never knew how good I had it with midterms! Going through a whole semester of material is unpleasant and because I didn’t think I had to worry about tests until all my classes were over they sort of snuck up on me. Oh well, you can retake things up to 4 times, which is kind of crazy, but things aren’t scaled at all like at home. Why did I decide I should try to get good grades? If I get solid Ds I’ll have a 4.0 the way grade averages work here, that’s plan B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to retake both exams I’ve taken so far (yuck).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">Had a great birthday! I got to go to my favorite market and then spend the day cooking for a relatively large group of groups of friends (15 people maybe?). Not a bad start to my late 20s (thanks for pointing out that milestone Han).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fireplace Cafe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/10/fireplaces.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fireplace Cafe" /><published>2022-01-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/10/fireplaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/10/fireplaces.html">&lt;p&gt;I found a whole list of cafes with fireplaces in Vienna but so far Café Jelenik is my favorite. To me it’s like the Viennese equivalent of a classic American diner, the food is cheap and comes in large portions (ok, Europe large) and you can choose from a limited array of traditional options. It feels like it’s in the only place it could exist in. The booths are upholstered in a green velvet that’s just a little bit shabby, which I think makes it more relaxing to spend a few hours chatting here.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fireplace_cafe/fire.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did think their collection of books was a little funny.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fireplace_cafe/manga.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also have the standard newspapers-on-wicker-frames that I think are really cool, but I didn’t get a picture so here’s one stolen from Google Maps that kind of features them:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fireplace_cafe/papers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">I found a whole list of cafes with fireplaces in Vienna but so far Café Jelenik is my favorite. To me it’s like the Viennese equivalent of a classic American diner, the food is cheap and comes in large portions (ok, Europe large) and you can choose from a limited array of traditional options. It feels like it’s in the only place it could exist in. The booths are upholstered in a green velvet that’s just a little bit shabby, which I think makes it more relaxing to spend a few hours chatting here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Entrapment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/07/trap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Entrapment" /><published>2022-01-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/07/trap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/07/trap.html">&lt;p&gt;I was walking to a subway station near the neighborhood my relatives lived in during the turn of the century (according to my mom) that is also the neighborhood that has the cutest Christmas market (according to me) and passed this sign (for kale):
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/trap/kale.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kale&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned into the alley and it became even clearer that someone had laid a trap for nearby millenials:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/trap/avocados.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;avocados&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to the store I realized it was a trap for me specifically (a sale on heirloom beans):
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/trap/beans.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;beans&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very cute! A little expensive but I did buy kale and beans (avocados here are for emergency use only). They had some tasty chocolate dipped spelt cookies too. I can’t get over that spelt is called “Dinkel” here so I feel driven to buy anything made with it. I can’t tell you why exactly this is so funny to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">I was walking to a subway station near the neighborhood my relatives lived in during the turn of the century (according to my mom) that is also the neighborhood that has the cutest Christmas market (according to me) and passed this sign (for kale):</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year’s Eve</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/01/nye.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year’s Eve" /><published>2022-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/01/nye</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/01/nye.html">&lt;p&gt;We went to hear Beethoven’s 9th at the Grosser Saal, apparently a new year’s tradition for a lot of people here. Bad snapchat picture, I realize.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/newyears.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;newyears&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hannah and I then went to a friend’s new years party (our only night to be fancy) and hung out with beers and went to a nearby bridge to watch the illegal fireworks people set off at midnight (and before midnight). The pictures of this are even worse so not included. I obnoxiously started video chats with friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At midnight everyone started waltzing, because this is Vienna. Hannah and I stepped on a lot of toes but people were patient and we had plenty of strangers to dance with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resolution&quot;&gt;Resolution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be more aware of how my habits increase or decrease my ability to focus: more regular exercise and books, less sugary food and tiktoks. Not to say I can never be irresponsible but just that when I am it should be fun enough to be worthwhile, not just a mediocre distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things I could learn from grad school would be how to be more self-driven. I really do enjoy my work when I’m in the zone, it just isn’t as instantly rewarding as getting angry about something on twitter or whatever my current distraction of choice is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think &lt;em&gt;A World without Email&lt;/em&gt;’s suggestion of thinking about yourself as having an “organizational mode” that sets you up for your “deep thinking mode” self to be successful might be a worthwhile approach. Next I want to read &lt;em&gt;Daily Rituals: How Artists Work&lt;/em&gt; because maybe that will help me glamorize having a consistent bedtime and making myself at least go on a walk every day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">We went to hear Beethoven’s 9th at the Grosser Saal, apparently a new year’s tradition for a lot of people here. Bad snapchat picture, I realize.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Salzburg</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/29/salzburg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Salzburg" /><published>2021-12-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/29/salzburg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/29/salzburg.html">&lt;p&gt;We made it to Salzburg after dark because of our Hallstatt stop but we did go to mom’s favorite beer hall from when she was a student (still there, maybe a few more animal skulls on the walls). No luck on the bar that’s in a cave where you could push 10 cent pieces into the soft rock until the whole area with in arms reach was silver (or at least this is the story I think I’ve been told). Still cool to just walk around, the city is built into the cliffs in a lot of places:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/cliff1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/cliff2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next morning we walked around the old city where we were staying (made parking a nightmare but convenient the next morning). Found a cool display of terrifying hedgehog postcards.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/array.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/ski.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really cool to be in the middle of a random street and then there’s a giant snowcapped mountain at the end of it. Unfortunately it’s a little hard to capture.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/berg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also hiked up to the castle (they let you get to the top before telling you you have to pay). 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/lion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the view was worth it.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;random-other-pictures&quot;&gt;Random other pictures:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only (grudging) recommendation I got from my Salzburger friend was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.220grad.com/locations/220grad-nonntal/&quot;&gt;a coffee shop&lt;/a&gt; and unfortunately we didn’t have time to stay. The coffee really was good though and the barista gave me tiny cookies for all four of us.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/coff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the fanciest vandalism I’ve ever seen.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/leaf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local beer loyalty.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salzburg/beer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">We made it to Salzburg after dark because of our Hallstatt stop but we did go to mom’s favorite beer hall from when she was a student (still there, maybe a few more animal skulls on the walls). No luck on the bar that’s in a cave where you could push 10 cent pieces into the soft rock until the whole area with in arms reach was silver (or at least this is the story I think I’ve been told). Still cool to just walk around, the city is built into the cliffs in a lot of places:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hallstatt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/28/hallstatt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hallstatt" /><published>2021-12-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/28/hallstatt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/28/hallstatt.html">&lt;p&gt;We knew we wanted to spend some time seeing more of Austria (partially to give our lovely host a break from us) so that we could visit Salzburg where mom studied abroad in college and where she and my dad went on their first trip together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hannah insisted on trying to go to Hallstatt too, despite the crazy additional train time and transfers it would take, all for a town that you can walk through in 20 minutes or so. Ultimately we decided to take a car to accommodate her wish (8 hour round trip train -&amp;gt; 1 hour car detour) and she totally made the right call. Even the drive was lovely:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/halstatt/stop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The town really is as cute as advertised: 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/halstatt/across.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently outside of covid it’s extremely popular but for now the tourists are really minimal.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/halstatt/carving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I’ll rush to come back here but I definitely need to go to &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; kind of beautifully clear mountain lake this summer:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/halstatt/clear.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did a little hike around nearby before heading to Salzburg. I hope this is for firewood an not people.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/halstatt/speed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">We knew we wanted to spend some time seeing more of Austria (partially to give our lovely host a break from us) so that we could visit Salzburg where mom studied abroad in college and where she and my dad went on their first trip together.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sachertorte</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/26/sacher.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sachertorte" /><published>2021-12-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/26/sacher</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/26/sacher.html">&lt;p&gt;Finally got to sneak into the “Blue Bar” at the Hotel Sacher, which is as fancy as it is cramped (very) with walls covered in peacock blue silk and intricate golden molding. Some friends and I have been getting turned in when we try to sneak in because it’s for hotel guests only in theory but I think they didn’t want to deal with us the day after Christmas.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sacher.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">Finally got to sneak into the “Blue Bar” at the Hotel Sacher, which is as fancy as it is cramped (very) with walls covered in peacock blue silk and intricate golden molding. Some friends and I have been getting turned in when we try to sneak in because it’s for hotel guests only in theory but I think they didn’t want to deal with us the day after Christmas.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Third Man</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/23/3rd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Third Man" /><published>2021-12-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/23/3rd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/23/3rd.html">&lt;p&gt;This is essentially another entry in the series of posts about how nice it is to live somewhere rent is cheap. Someone liked a classic movie set here enough to dedicate three store fronts to displaying his personal collection of Japanese record releases of the soundtrack etc.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/3rd_man/poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum is open one day a week and otherwise you have to request that they open it for you on a specific day. It’s not like this is in the middle of nowhere either, it’s right by my school. It’s a good movie if you get the chance to watch it but dang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also has some interesting historical information about the time period the movie was shot in: the ground was still covered in the rubble from WWII bombings and the city was split into four quarters like Berlin. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/3rd_man/quart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family also made time to go on the ferris wheel from the climax of the film. This picture roughly points at my new apartment.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/3rd_man/wheel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack holds up, actually, if you like increasingly frantic zither playing (and I do, apparently).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/1jWbae7ESwl2fWHGwcLvLk?utm_source=generator&amp;amp;theme=0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">This is essentially another entry in the series of posts about how nice it is to live somewhere rent is cheap. Someone liked a classic movie set here enough to dedicate three store fronts to displaying his personal collection of Japanese record releases of the soundtrack etc.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Drink in a Bar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/23/sis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Drink in a Bar" /><published>2021-12-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/23/sis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/23/sis.html">&lt;p&gt;I got to buy Hannah her first drink in a bar even though it isn’t her 21st birthday.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sis/han.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the fancy bar we went and got schnitzel, fries, and tallboys from a street cart while it was raining and Hannah drank the rest of her beer after we both dropped them on the ground :’) I’m no longer on that level, that’s how I know I’m getting old, I donated mine to the storm drain. I think we did a good job running the gamut of drinking experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also checked out some places I’ve been meaning to go. 12 euros for curried lentils should be a crime but the place is so pretty!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sis/palm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">I got to buy Hannah her first drink in a bar even though it isn’t her 21st birthday.</summary></entry></feed>