<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-14T23:41:34+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vienna Blog</title><subtitle>A (nearly) no-CSS, fast, minimalist Jekyll theme.
#favicon: &quot;logo.png&quot; # name+extension of favicon (which must be put on the root folder)
</subtitle><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><entry><title type="html">Christmas Markets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/14/christmasmarkets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas Markets" /><published>2021-11-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/14/christmasmarkets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/14/christmasmarkets.html">&lt;p&gt;There are Christmas markets and I took photos!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">There are Christmas markets and I took photos!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/IMG_20211112_180154815.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/IMG_20211112_180154815.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">School</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="School" /><published>2021-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/school</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/school.html">&lt;p&gt;One of my first days in Vienna I went to check out campus since I was living nearby at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t gone into the library yet because covid limitations plus a reservation system I can’t figure out means I keep getting turned away. The outside has this funky 70s owl that I’m quite fond of though. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/owl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;owl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some architectural whiplash, the main campus is near Karlsplatz:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/karl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;karl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS building isn’t as impactful but I do like the metal letters floating over the building.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/csbuilding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first school event was an orientation that included free beer :’) and turned into more late night beers in the courtyard and then even later beers in the park in front of the church. The amount of casual outside drinking blows my mind every time it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, this is the first day that I started to realize my worries about making new friends would be overblown. I think it’s a combination of the school mindset–people are in meet-new-people mode–and the reopening after covid mindset.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/school/intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;intro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">One of my first days in Vienna I went to check out campus since I was living nearby at the time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leaving</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/23/leaving.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leaving" /><published>2021-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/23/leaving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/23/leaving.html">&lt;p&gt;Got down to three bags + backpack before leaving the US in September.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/stuff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;stuff&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why Vienna?” is a question I get from a lot of people (espeically the locals) so I feel like I have my set of answers at this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was ready for a change in scenery but wasn’t excited enough about any particular place in the US to try to move there. I also credit Marina Milan as a major inspiration/role model because she actually acted on the feeling that she needed a change of pace even if life at home was good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I speak some German (quickly and quietly so people don’t catch my mistakes or anything at all that I’m saying) but the program is in English so I don’t need to speak &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much German.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a great deal! School is much cheaper, even for a master’s degree unlike some of the cash cow masters degrees at home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have some friends from home who live here and can help me when I need it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel like I didn’t take enough advantage of the summer I spent here in high school so this is round 2!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The program is suprisingly exactly what I want to do: a master’s degree in CS that focuses on math, formal methods, and logic instead of generic software development or a specialty that doesn’t interest me like machine learning. When I found it I felt a little like the stars were aligning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a retroactive blog post but all the reasoning above has held up and the transition has been surprisingly smooth!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alice Lee</name></author><summary type="html">Got down to three bags + backpack before leaving the US in September.</summary></entry></feed>